redis an in-memory multi-model database famous for its sub-millisecond latency
redis 是一个内存中的多模型数据库，以其亚毫秒级延迟而闻名。
it was created in 2009 based on the idea that a cache can also be a durable data
它创建于 2009 年，基于这样一种想法，即缓存也可以是一个持久的数据
store around this time apps like twitter were
存储，大约在这个时候，像 twitter 这样的应用程序
growing exponentially and needed a way to deliver data to their end users
呈指数级增长，需要一种交付方式 向最终用户发送数据的
faster than a relational database could handle
速度比关系数据库处理
redis which means remote dictionary server was adopted by some of the most
redis 的速度更快，这意味着远程字典服务器被世界上一些流量最大的
heavily trafficked sites in the world because it changed the database game by
网站采用，因为它通过
creating a system where data is always modified or read from the main computer
创建一个始终修改或读取数据的系统改变了数据库游戏 主计算机
memory as opposed to the much slower disk but
内存而不是慢得多的磁盘，但
at the same time it stores its data on the disk so it can
同时它将其数据存储在磁盘上，因此可以根据需要对其
be reconstructed as needed which means the database is
进行重建，这意味着数据库是
fully durable supporting things like snapshots and backups every data point
完全持久的，支持快照和备份之类的东西
in the database is a key followed by one of many different data
数据库中的每个数据点都是 键后跟许多不同的数据结构之一，
structures like a string list hash or stream so you can store
例如字符串列表哈希或流，因此
data naturally just like you would with your favorite programming language as
您可以像使用您的收藏一样自然地存储数据
opposed to squeezing it into a bunch of tables or json documents
与将其压缩成一堆表或 json 文档相比
interacting with the database is handled with a simple set of commands
，与数据库交互的编程语言是通过一组简单的命令来处理的，
like set followed by a key and value to create data
例如 set 后跟一个键和值来创建数据，
then git followed by a key to read data historically
然后 git 后跟一个键来读取历史数据
redis has been described as a key value store and is often used as a cache to
redis 已被描述为键值存储，并且通常用作缓存以
make relational databases faster at scale
使关系数据库在规模上更快，
but here's where your mind is about to be blown redis is perfectly suitable as
但在这里你的想法即将被吹走 redis 非常适合
a primary database and can dramatically reduce complexity
作为主数据库，并且可以显着降低复杂性，
because making things go fast at scale is the primary cause of complexity in
因为让事情变得更快 大规模是复杂性的主要原因
the first place with redis your database is already fast
首先使用 redis 你的数据库已经很快了
no need for a complex caching layer but you might be wondering
不需要复杂的缓存层但是你可能想
how do i model complex relationships today redis is what you would call
知道我今天如何建模复杂的关系redis 就是你所说
a multi-model database supporting a variety of different database paradigms
的多模型数据库支持 带有附加模块的各种不同的数据库范例
with add-on modules that you can opt into as
，
needed if your data contains relationships bring in redis graph
如果您的数据包含关系，您可以根据需要选择加入 是图形
and query it with cipher or use the json module to structure your data as a
并使用密码查询它，或者使用 json模块将您的数据结构化为
hierarchy just like a document-oriented database
层次结构，就像面向文档的数据库一样，
then use the search module to turn your database into a full text
然后使用搜索模块将您的数据库变成全文
search engine and it even has modules for ai workloads time series data
搜索引擎，它甚至还有用于 AI 工作负载时间的模块 系列数据
and more the quickest way to get started is the free tier on redis enterprise
等 最快的入门方式是 redis 企业云上的免费层，
cloud that'll give you a free database to play around with and you can attach
它会给你一个免费的数据库来玩，你可以附加
one extra module to it then you can connect to it with the redis cli or with
一个额外的模块，然后你可以使用 redis cli 连接到它或
the redis insight tool which contains an interactive dashboard to manage your
使用 redis 洞察工具，其中包含一个交互式仪表板来管理您的
data this has been redis in 100 seconds but what do you guys think would you use
数据，这在 100 秒内就是 redis，但是你们认为您会使用
redis as your primary database let me know why or why not
redis 作为您的主数据库吗？让我知道为什么或为什么
in the comments thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
不在评论中感谢您的观看，我 下一篇见